<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on tbobm.dev</title>
    <link>https://blog.tbobm.dev/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on tbobm.dev</description>
    <image>
      <title>tbobm.dev</title>
      <url>https://blog.tbobm.dev/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://blog.tbobm.dev/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.119.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 17:17:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tbobm.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Row Level changes in PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>https://blog.tbobm.dev/posts/row-level-database-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 17:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tbobm.dev/posts/row-level-database-tracking/</guid>
      <description>Ownerships and modification dates often have a huge role in troubleshooting or understanding how applications work. Making last change metadata available can be a game changer in case of bug hunting or to understand how data behaves without digging through logs for hours.
Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in a way of automating this &amp;ldquo;last update&amp;rdquo; tracking at the row level in Postgresql.
Code is available at github.com/tbobm/postgresql-row-level-changes
Automatically Tracking Row-Level Changes in PostgreSQL Managing changes to database records is a crucial part of maintaining data integrity and transparency in a system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://blog.tbobm.dev/posts/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 13:27:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.tbobm.dev/posts/now/</guid>
      <description>Current topics I work on and main interests.
I love to post stuff on Github and a lot of my stuff is public: github.com/tbobm
TLDR I like to work with highly scalable, efficient and reliable architectures (ideally by building them). Most of my recent experiences have been focused on Media Processing, offering a nice sandbox to try out Event Driven architectures.
Coding is now a great part of my day to day life, with a strong intention to write self maintainable code, easy to ready and most importantly, simple things that just work.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
